we're back
again
on hermitcraft and we're working on the
mansion again last episode i managed to
get quite a bit of the walls done and
today i really want to see if i can get
this whole thing covered a little better
no details again but just trying to fill
the enormous gap that has been left for
quite some time now i did run out of
resources and that's why i had to stop
but i've stocked up we are ready to go
on this thing
but before that
i want to tell you about my plans for
the emporium over in the shopping
district i actually got rid of my cow
farm that used to be here and with the
mayoral campaign beginning there's two
things that i feel
we could sell a lot of
and those are two of the most annoying
items in the game to craft
item frames
and empty maps
hey look
mumbo for mayor
so i thought with everyone
wanting to put their maps and put put
their items in frames everywhere i
thought what we could do is supply this
in the emporium and for that i'm gonna
need more than just these three cows
so
much like i've done in the past we're
gonna have to breed these guys up
and then
we're gonna have to turn them into these
things
it's a bit cruel really but
gotta be done
so let's seal this thing up so that they
can't escape let's get our week together
and start
to get as much leather as possible
everything else i got enough of but
leather
commodity
okay let's get this done
[Music]
the time lapse didn't actually show how
long i actually went on for it kept
going that one's having a party by
itself this should be a decent amount of
leather right
right
okay it's time it's time to get rid of
them all i'm sorry i'm sorry
sorry this makes it so much worse if you
put wheat in your offhand
oh they then they come to you oh no
i'm an animal lover i promise
i promise
oh my goodness the lag is insane
this is one of the unfortunate realities
of minecraft what have i become
oh my goodness doing stuff like this
looks like it doesn't take long but
actually it took two and a half hours to
get this many cows and i don't feel
particularly good about it we have got
ourselves a lot of leather
this will make well just as many item
frames which is exactly what we need and
i feel like i'm entitled i'm justified
in charging quite a lot of diamonds for
a stack of these because it's quite a
lot of work doing that right we'll put
this away for the time being and what
we'll do
is actually get started on our next
project which will be just finishing up
some work on the back of the mansion
just filling in that gap a little bit
more probably not going to do too much
today but we'll get some of this done
just enough
okay so
let's let's hop into another time lapse
and let's get let's get some bass done i
want to make a little bit of progress
every single episode if i can let's go
[Music]
and i think that's a pretty good place
to stop i've got everything all lined
off at the correct height but i can't
really do a lot more without knowing
exactly how i'm going to detail all of
these spots so um
i don't really want to freestyle this as
i've said before this is quite a
delicate build especially you don't want
to be messing around with two block
diagonal builds you really gotta think
things through and plan it out this is
as far as i can go without more
information on how i want to detail this
exactly but
you can see it's slowly closing in and
coming together and i'm very excited
about that but i've also stopped because
i have received a message from the one
the only the king of the spanner base
mumbo jumbo leo himself
who has told me
that it
the grumbot
is ready oh my goodness look at his base
i i actually really like mumbo's bass
it's very very different to what i'm
doing
he's got like a
thing going on i don't even i don't even
know the words to describe it but he
said meet me at the grambot and we shall
make it work for the first time i'm so
excited oh my goodness the sun's setting
behind grumba he looks so majestic
yeah though he does look really really
cool so i've built up all the redstone
i've developed artificial intelligence
in minecraft making use of redstone you
know i'm quite proud of myself on that
one it took a day a day
cracked artificial intelligence like
that just took a day really long
yeah so um it should it should all be
working and we should be able to start
asking it questions and things okay how
does it how does it work
okay okay yeah i'll explain that to you
but yeah so what we've got is we've got
this dropper right here this is the
important dropper because this dropper
is actually what is going to give out
the merrell advice okay so this is like
super super important so this is output
and then we have the different stages of
priming all of which are incredibly
important prime grambot
step two bootload brain
boot load brain incredibly important
okay step three flood mayoral reservoir
what does that even mean what does flood
mean you just got to flood the
reservoirs you know you just gotta get
them flooded and
meryle you may be maybe the first humans
ever to use that sequence of words flood
mayoral reservoir that might have never
been said before
i would be surprised and now i'm curious
the situation is someone else used it
okay
deposit question diamond yes deposit
what does that mean
well you have to
yeah you have to name a diamond and then
that's that's what you put the question
in and then yeah you make your payment
you designed a machine that we have to
pay to use
oh yeah yeah
yeah i was the one that built this why
did i make it charged
i mean i just thought you know like you
know he probably has feelings too he is
an artificial intelligence he doesn't
want to be doing this for free
everyone on this server needs or just
wants diamonds as all anyone cares about
even the things that we create they want
diamonds i know i know it's a real
problem right well should we should we
start chucking questions into this thing
i've only done tests so far okay i'm
really curious if it actually does
work what is our slogan would that be a
good one yeah what is our slogan we
should know the answer because we know
the answer to this one right yeah yeah
yeah
this is like a this is like a
affirmation like if he gets this right
we know it's working
right okay okay so step one you need to
prime him
oh it goes
there's only one thing better than a
button it's a button that goes beep
exactly exactly right do you want to do
the honors what is our slogan all right
all right it's calculating the
calculating
yes
nice okay
it's like a proper that's like a proper
thinking like
yeah yeah
let's really let's really go to town on
this what is the meaning of life
what no
wait wait wait no this is a merrell bot
man
well i mean it is an artificial
intelligence
i mean
you said you cracked ai and there it
goes
doesn't mean that it's that smart dude
come on grandma
you got an answer for us he has an
answer he presented an answer
it says mumbo for mayor
oh well
i mean
is that the meaning of life i mean it
could be the meaning of life i certainly
feel like it's the meaning of life i
think it's the meaning of life for
grumbach
maybe you're right maybe it's his
personal meaning for life
or maybe it's a bug you know maybe maybe
maybe it can only say
it just says mumbo from there no matter
what we put in
um uh should i ask it can it say
anything different because it seems like
it would be an important thing
to turn to to work out so can you say
can it say anything other than mumbo for
mayor right so the question is primed
can you say anything different i think
that's that's descriptive yeah yeah yeah
can you say anything different okay it's
also part of this conversation
yep
[Music]
i love it i love it so much it's
satisfying
oh i think we might have insulted his
intelligence a little bit
i think
what's he saying
yes but grumbot does not want to
is that really his
[Laughter]
oh response him
look have you put emotions in a robot
because this is literally how every
movie goes badly when you give robots
emotions
i might have done that mate yeah i might
have done that mate we need to ask him
what we do now what do we do now we
built this thing so that he could tell
us what to do we need to ask him what we
do so what are we asking him we are
asking him uh what guess what's the plan
what do we do what's the plan what's the
plan
yes what's the plan okay we keep it
intentionally vague soon
nothing can go wrong all right all right
flood those mayoral reservoirs
[Music]
i mean it's a fun thing to use yeah
oh we're gonna get a bristle
yay
oh
oh he's angry
we've annoyed him oh we've annoyed him
what does he want grumbot needs budget
we
dude we just gave you four diamonds mate
what dude what's created what have you
you've created a robe an intelligent
robot that demands diamonds not only to
ask him questions but he just he wants
more diamonds
but i suppose i mean
maybe hands
i mean it kind of makes sense because if
he's going to tell us to do something we
need to get in the diamonds to make it
okay okay grumpy of course you got it
we'll get you diamonds yes sir yes sir
praise
okay well i guess i guess that's our
task then we need to get budget yeah and
then we can come back and i'm giving in
my diamond i'm going mining
right yeah yeah we'll have to find
exterior diamonds
all right well i guess i mean that's the
plan we need budget and then when we
come back we can start asking more
questions once we've got a budget and we
can we can kind of go from there how
does that sound i feel like we've
created a monster i definitely think
we've created
we've both invested far too much time
into this we now have to abide by
everything
we've done
we have to live with this decision
all right let's go let's go get some
budget
grumble says we need budget so
i guess that's where we're going next to
get some budget oh my goodness what is
this
oh so we can tell who's like who's the
most supported hermit hello mumbo jumbo
with three supporters i'm i'm assuming
one of those is mumbo
and i haven't done this yet so there's
two mystery supporters for mumbo
oh it looks like our competition is scar
but i'm about to take this
i'm about to take this to the next level
yes
ah yes mumbo is clearly in the lead
the poster is the plan people
so now we need to go and we need to get
ourselves some diamonds
oh no
the button
what happened
rip button
15th of april to 26th of may 41 good
days of life
no
my powers
what happens to my gauntlet
no
my powers
and my hand it's back to normal
why didn't i use it more
all i did was click some doors out of
existence oh what a what a waste of an
opportunity well i guess the the corpse
of the button stays there right we need
to go and we need to do some pretty
heavy mining i actually i don't know how
much budget
grumbot needs
probably
i don't know who can't how much budget
does a robot need scar did create the
diamond mine which i didn't really use
that much so maybe i can get in touch
with scar and see if he actually wants
to do whatever he had planned with this
because i now need
diamonds scar
yes you remember the start of the season
when you built this thing the the
diamond mine and you said hey i'm going
to make this mining minigame and we're
going to play and then we never did yeah
it was the diamond challenge mine yeah
that didn't didn't quite happen but i
actually do need diamonds now so i'm
like yeah do you want to play oh i'm up
for i'm up for a game one hour mining
session and we see who gets the most
diamonds
so we're finally gonna play we're gonna
play we're gonna play all this work
honestly oh this is amazing and oh this
is fantastic i like your new outfit a
lot oh why thank you are you the man
from powerpuff girls
people keep saying powerpuff girls i do
not know what a powerpuff girl is
really i don't know all you need is a
monocle and you are straight up the
mayor from powerpuff girls oh it has a
monocle let me let me get you here let
me get i got you don't worry yeah okay
seriously
you are you are him you are the man from
powerpuff girls um speaking of which
here you go take a take a gander at that
it's just that's for you
oh i have i have like 20 of these in my
shop now um but you can take one of my
signs
it doesn't have anything on it you can
write vote for scar if you want to be
polite oh well what an amazing campaign
cool
look at my outfit come on mumbo just not
walking around looking like this a man
walks into her into a room like this
people take notice people stop people go
i wonder what his opinion is no no no
what they say is is that the mayor from
powerpuff girls
[Laughter]
okay right what's what's the the shindig
down here we go we just go straight down
the bottom oh yeah i was going to build
a diamond counter and all this stuff but
i never got to it sadly there's just a
sign on the wall here it is sign on the
wall nothing
we'll make our own rules explain away
first of all you have to uh pay homage
to the um this block is haunted never
touch it um
this is my tunnel and that is your
tunnel and uh i really wanna find it
indeed
oh no it would haunt your life if you
did i i wouldn't oh wait i put that
there
oh you did yeah i put that there dude if
you go back to episode two or three of
mine there's a whole story behind this
block like
my pickaxe broke a bit over it it was a
whole thing this literally is haunted
i found this and i just put it there and
i don't pretty simple right we we go
each go our own direction
first but well after an hour we see who
gets the most diamonds but what's the
stakes who what's the prize um you
temporarily support me or i temporarily
support mumbo
deal
deal yes deal
how dude it would be see i'm just a
campaign manager right but you're
actually running for mayor so if you if
you actually have to go and support
someone else that is terrible
that is
you're on
do you think my campaign sergeant would
be upset about about that maybe yeah
maybe a little bit
but i think it's a good deal i'm taking
the risk and taking the risk all right
let's go all right goodbye
one hour let's go
[Music]
time's up scar
time to surface i'm nearly at the top
yeah i walked i walked back to the
center of the mine where are you i am
hold on
i went i went on quite an adventure i've
no idea where i am
where are you
[Laughter]
are you still in the mine area hold on
let me catch my bearings i don't
recognize that building or that building
dude i'm at corrales base
i'm i literally mined all the way
i went on quite an adventure i went
through mumbo's mine i went through like
maybe two or three other mine shafts and
somehow i've ended up at corrales city
oh my goodness this place looks amazing
oh i want to see i just mined one way
and came back the other way how boring
that was probably smart all right i'm on
my way back all right scott time to
time to total up here we go this is what
i got
64. diamond door on the dot you got 61.
i got 61. but i got 61. in all fairness
it's not over yet because we're gonna
we're going to mine all of this and
we're going to see what we get with our
looting with our fortune sorry fortune
and we'll see who gets the most diamonds
because we're after diamonds not diamond
doors in all fairness
so so you're saying there's a chance
there is a chance depends how lucky both
of us get and to be fair that mining
session was terrible like i did not get
many diamonds at all really all right so
we're gonna tower up yep here we go here
we go
so in theory mine should be three blocks
taller than yours
racy to the bottom good luck
oh
here we go
and last one i had a stack so i have
been very lucky
oh
what in the world you're what three
extra blocks gave you that many extra
diamonds no overall i was i was luckier
right because i had a stack of diamonds
and there's a there's like a one in
three chance right so
yeah it on on by average the law of
averages you would expect to double your
diamonds because you could either get
one two or three
mm-hmm i'm gonna take my shame diamonds
out of the box do you know where we need
to get you know where we need to go now
right um
oh jelly needs fit no
get get get back here you need to go and
put your
support
for mumbo that pdf is going to look down
on me yeah thing yeah but we shook on it
we should oh no no yeah i wanted to no
no
no all right i need to say the words as
well oh i want you to say the words come
on let's go come on scar
i'm coming it's time
come on
and this is gonna really hurt because i
just checked and you are actually one
block above mumbo we got some i don't
know who these secret supporters are
but it's time press the button
oh green team no
but i'm winning press the button
you lost the bet
that's true
that's true oh that hurts oh that hurts
and what does that mean i gotta go over
here then red put a red one for mumbo
uh everyone and you gotta say the words
you gotta say the words say the words on
the map
say the words oh what was that again
i've got two maps now how many maps do
you have i have uh mumbai from here
okay
he said it we kind of whispered it but
he said it boom
mumbo is currently in the lead with the
poles
wow
all right
i'll see you later
is going to be so mad at me yeah he is
just
i have to see him in 10 minutes
this is uh this is how we campaign
make people lose bets
so
let's put all of these diamonds into
blocks and it's uh only 17 blocks
that's not actually that many oh dear we
should really find out whether grumbot's
gonna be okay with this as a budget
let's take this over to grumbot and see
what he says hello my new shiny friend
let's see what you have to say right i'm
gonna put my diamonds over here on this
hand
as tribute and see what he thinks
yeah 17 blocks isn't actually that much
turns out well there's my contribution
and then we'll wait for mumbo's
contribution of diamonds
i've got my diamond let's let's ask him
the question
is this enough
prime grumbot
boo boo boo load the brain
flood the mayoral reservoir
and deposit the diamond question
bristle bristle
yay
and he's oh he's not he's neither happy
nor sad this time
grumbot needs more budget
grambot needs more budget
i guess that makes sense i've put in my
diamonds
mumbo it's down to you now so mumbo oh
man look at the sunset over grumbot it's
beautiful finally get to enjoy it as
well
so there's my diamonds now just waiting
on mumbo to do his now next episode i
don't know if it will be next episode
but i really want to upgrade the
emporium one more time
i i feel like i just keep getting to the
stage like oh i'm not sure what i'm
gonna do here and then i'm like yeah i
know what i'm gonna do and then i just
have more insane ideas for this place
and more stock that i can supply and it
looks like it's still successful oh my
goodness diamonds galore
wow this is this is really profitable
i'm not gonna lie this is doing well i
think i think that a stack and nearly a
stack and a half of diamonds that's
almost certainly enough to upgrade this
yet again it cost me about a stack of
diamonds to upgrade it last time
well we'll do it again but that will
have to be in the next episode because
i'm afraid we have run out of time yet
again that was like a slow roll that
time so there's nothing left to say
except thank you very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed this episode and i
shall see you
in the next one
good
bye
greedy grumbot needs more diamonds what
do you know